Give 'Em Hell, John.
Rio Lobo is a western film directed by Howard Hawks.
After the Civil War, a former Union colonel searches for the two
traitors whose perfidy led to the loss of a close friend.
Col. Cord McNally, played by John Wayne.
Capt. Pierre Cordona, played by Jorge Rivero.
Shasta Delaney, played by Jennifer O'Neill.
Phillips, played by Jack Elam.
Sgt. Tuscarora Phillips, played by Christopher Mitchum.
Ketcham, played by Victor French.
Rio Lobo is a 1970 American Western film directed and produced by Howard Hawks—his final film—starring John
Wayne, based on a screenplay by Burton Wohl and Leigh Brackett, and composed by Jerry Goldsmith.
The film was shot in Cuernavaca in the Mexican state
of Morelos and in Tucson, Arizona.
It was the third Howard Hawks film to explore the theme of a town sheriff defending his office against belligerent
local outlaws; the others were Rio Bravo (1959) and El Dorado (1966), both also starring John Wayne.
The film explores themes of sheriff, traitor, texas, colonel.